{
    "1": {
        "question" : "Who was the creator of Star Trek?",
        "answer" : "b",
        "a" : "George Lucas",
        "b" : "Gene Roddenbery",
        "c" : "Leonard Nimoy",
        "d" : "J. J. Abrams",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "2": {
        "question" : "How long was the USS Enterprise's mission supposed to last?",
        "answer" : "b",
        "a" : "3 years",
        "b" : "5 years",
        "c" : "10 years",
        "d" : "Never stated",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "3": {
        "question" : "Where did Captain James Kirk serve before the USS Enterprise?",
        "answer" : "c",
        "a" : "USS Republic",
        "b" : "USS Summit",
        "c" : "USS Farragut",
        "d" : "USS Defiant",
        "e" : "None - he had a desk job"
    },
    "4": {
        "question" : "How many seasons did the original series run for?",
        "answer" : "c",
        "a" : "1",
        "b" : "2",
        "c" : "3",
        "d" : "4",
        "e" : "None - there was only a pilot"
    },
    "5": {
        "question" : "Scotty was played by James Doohan. What country is James originally from?",
        "answer" : "c",
        "a" : "Scotland",
        "b" : "USA",
        "c" : "Canada",
        "d" : "Australia",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "6": {
        "question" : "Amanda Grayson, Spock's mother, was very fond of one author. Who was her favorite writer?",
        "answer" : "a",
        "a" : "Lewis Carroll",
        "b" : "Ernest Hemingway",
        "c" : "Jack London",
        "d" : "William Shakespeare",
        "e" : "F. Scott Fitzgerald"
    },
    "7": {
        "question" : "The original Star Trek series took place over how many years?",
        "answer" : "c",
        "a" : "1 year",
        "b" : "3 years",
        "c" : "5 years",
        "d" : "10 years",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "8": {
        "question" : "Leo Francis Walsh was a known galactic criminal and a con man. What was his real name?",
        "answer" : "c",
        "a" : "Roger Charles Carmel",
        "b" : "Zefram Cochrane",
        "c" : "Harcourt Fenton Mudd",
        "d" : "Christopher Pike",
        "e" : "That was his name"
    },
    "9": {
        "question" : "Originally, the creators of the show intended for Spock to be from Mars. Later, however, they changed it to Vulcan. Why?",
        "answer" : "b",
        "a" : "They thought it was too similar to George Welles' novel War of the Worlds",
        "b" : "They thought that humans would walk on Mars soon after the show was launched",
        "c" : "They wanted something more exotic than a planet from our Solar System",
        "d" : "At the time of the creation of Star Trek they knew Mars was basically a desert",
        "e" : "If men were from Mars, the women would have to be from Venus"
    },
    "10": {
        "question" : "Where was James T. Kirk born?",
        "answer" : "b",
        "a" : "Arizona",
        "b" : "Iowa",
        "c" : "Moonbase Alpha",
        "d" : "He was born in space onboard the USS Farragut",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "11": {
        "question" : "What separates the Federation from Romulon space?",
        "answer" : "c",
        "a" : "A energy field",
        "b" : "Delta quadrant",
        "c" : "The Neutral Zone",
        "d" : "Klingon Empire",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "11": {
        "question" : "What year did the original series first air?",
        "answer" : "d",
        "a" : "1954",
        "b" : "1961",
        "c" : "1975",
        "d" : "1967",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "12": {
        "question" : "Who was supporting the people of planet Neural with weapons (Episode 19, Season 2, 'A Private Little War')?",
        "answer" : "b",
        "a" : "Romulans",
        "b" : "Klingons",
        "c" : "Humans",
        "d" : "Andorians",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "13": {
        "question" : "Who designed the costumes for the Star Trek crew?",
        "answer" : "b",
        "a" : "Jack Pierce",
        "b" : "Bill Theiss",
        "c" : "John Caglione",
        "d" : "Stan Winston",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "14": {
        "question" : "What was the invention of Zefram Cochrane?",
        "answer" : "c",
        "a" : "Replicators",
        "b" : "Holodeck",
        "c" : "Warp Drive Technology",
        "d" : "Transporter",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "15": {
        "question" : "What does toilet paper and the USS Enterprise have in common",
        "answer" : "a",
        "a" : "They both circle uranus looking for klingons",
        "b" : "Nothing they didn't have toilet paper in space",
        "c" : "They both have 2 ply",
        "d" : "This is a joke right?",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "16": {
        "question" : "Whose voice was the Enterprise computer?",
        "answer" : "c",
        "a" : "Nicelle Nichols",
        "b" : "Majel Barrett",
        "c" : "James Earl Jones",
        "d" : "HAL 9000",
        "e" : "None - it was synthesised"
    },
    "17": {
        "question" : "The physiology of the alien race Horta, that caused problems in the mines of Janus VI, is based on which element?",
        "answer" : "b",
        "a" : "Lithium",
        "b" : "Silicon",
        "c" : "Carbon",
        "d" : "Sulpur",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "18": {
        "question" : "In one episode, James T. Kirk engaged himself in a fight against an individual of the Gorn race on the surface of a desert planet. What was the title of the episode?",
        "answer" : "a",
        "a" : "Arena",
        "b" : "The Enemy Within",
        "c" : "The Neutral Zone",
        "d" : "Space Seed",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "19": {
        "question" : "One of the members of the crew was chief communications officer Uhura. Her name comes from Swahili word 'uhuru'. What does it mean?",
        "answer" : "e",
        "a" : "Light",
        "b" : "Ebony",
        "c" : "Star",
        "d" : "Hope",
        "e" : "Freedom"
    },
    "20": {
        "question" : "What color is Vulcan blood",
        "answer" : "b",
        "a" : "Red",
        "b" : "Green",
        "c" : "Yellow",
        "d" : "Blue",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "21": {
        "question" : "Dr. McCoy was played by what actor",
        "answer" : "b",
        "a" : "James Doohan",
        "b" : "DeForest Kelley",
        "c" : "Leonard Nimoy",
        "d" : "George Takei",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "22": {
        "question" : "What is Dr. McCoy's nickname",
        "answer" : "b",
        "a" : "Dr. Death",
        "b" : "Bones",
        "c" : "Doc",
        "d" : "Mac",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "23": {
        "question" : "How many episodes are in the Original Series",
        "answer" : "c",
        "a" : "75",
        "b" : "80",
        "c" : "79",
        "d" : "100",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "24": {
        "question" : "What size crew did Captain Kirk command aboard the Enterprise?",
        "answer" : "a",
        "a" : "430",
        "b" : "200",
        "c" : "1030",
        "d" : "500",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "25": {
        "question" : "In TV's original Star Trek series, how did a salt shaker serve as a prop on early episodes?",
        "answer" : "c",
        "a" : "Communicator",
        "b" : "Listening Device",
        "c" : "Medical Scanner",
        "d" : "Grenade",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "26": {
        "question" : "In TV's Star Trek, who commanded the U.S.S. Enterprise Before Capt. James T. Kirk took command?",
        "answer" : "d",
        "a" : "Captain Janeway",
        "b" : "Captain Archer",
        "c" : "Captain America",
        "d" : "Captain Pike",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "27": {
        "question" : "What is in Mr. Spock's blood that gives him green skin?",
        "answer" : "c",
        "a" : "Bronze and Copper",
        "b" : "Chlorophyll",
        "c" : "Copper and Nickel",
        "d" : "Green M&Ms",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "28": {
        "question" : "In the original draft for the Star Trek TV series what was the name of the U.S.S. Enterprise?",
        "answer" : "c",
        "a" : "USS Voyager",
        "b" : "USS Intrepid",
        "c" : "USS Yorktown",
        "d" : "USS Asimov",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "29": {
        "question" : "What was antimatter used for on the starship Enterprise?",
        "answer" : "c",
        "a" : "Makes the transporter work",
        "b" : "Allows you to go back and forth through time",
        "c" : "Powers the warp engines",
        "d" : "Prevents alternate realities from destroying the current reality",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "30": {
        "question" : "Before gaining fame on Star Trek, in what movie did actor Leonard Nimoy first appear as an alien from outer space?",
        "answer" : "c",
        "a" : "Cowboys and Aliens",
        "b" : "Rawhide",
        "c" : "In The Zombie Vanguard",
        "d" : "Earth Girls are Easy",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    }
}
